Jess Dowd

Front End | Web Developer | Software Engineer

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | jessalyndowd@gmail.com | +66 62-398-6762 | MO, USA (Remote)

Summary

Full stack developer bootcamp student with 1+ year of experience in web development. Seeking a full-time position available to start immediately to use proven React skills to meet business needs. I am a Finance Major with a background in eCommerce and I find an interesting crossover between my software and my business experience. Both pursuits challenge so many aspects of the intellect: creativity, organization, sequential processing, problem-solving.

Technical Skills | Languages | Tools

HTML5 - CSS3 - JavaScript/JSX - React - CRA - SQL and jQuery - API - OOP - React components - React Hooks Algorithms - Continuous Integration (CI) - Data Structures - Deployment - Unit Testing Webpack - Babel - JSON - SQL - DOM - Debugging - SCSS - Form validation - Git/GitHub - Figma - NPM flexbox - grid layout - BEM - Media queries - transition - CSS Frameworks - Styled-Components English (Native), Thai (Basic, A2), Mandarin (Beginner, A1)

Technical Projects

Around the U.S - React - 07/2021 Website | Demo | Code files

Front-end App using API to fetch data, CSS and jquery to create adaptive layout and JSX, React CRA to add interactivity

- Built maintainable, reusable UI components using API and JS
- Successfully implemented webpack and Babel to increase load speed
- Recently moved the relevant codebase from jQuery/vanilla JS to React

From Portland to Portland - 10/2020 Website | Code files

Front-end Application built with HTML and using CSS grid to display adaptive array of photos

- Used media queries to build a smooth UX/UI across all platforms (iPhone, Android, Tablet)
- Created pixel-perfect recreations of designer mock-ups from figma

Education

Practicum by Yandex | Intensive Web Development program | 2020-2021

- Completed 10 independent projects using languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSX, JS frameworks, libraries like React, and industry best practice standards for clean code.
- Worked with classmates two week long sprints to gain experience for software development process
- Project-based course. The curriculum provides a wide range of projects based on current Full Stack Development technologies

Bachelor in Business Administration (B.B.A) | Burapha University | 2019-2024

- Studies Global Business Administration and Finance
- Elected Major Leader of Finance for the class of 2020 GPA 3.75

Experience

Freelance | Web Developer | 04/2021 - Current

- Design and build websites using technologies JSX, CSS, NextJs and ReactJS.
- Built personal website for a process engineer. Researched and improved overall site interaction and design.

Ecommerce WordPress | Manager - Jessential | 2013 - 2017

• Built e-commerce store, inventory management, product development, label and logo design,